Guide to the Alternative Press Collection, 1967-1977
Vassar College Libraries Archives and Special Collections
Alternative Press Collection
1967-1977
1.4 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections, Vassar College Libraries
Miscellaneous collection of radical, leftist, feminist, and other alternative periodicals from the 1960s and 1970s.
Scope and Content Note
Miscellaneous collection of radical, leftist, feminist, and other alternative periodicals from the 1960s and 1970s.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Feminism--Periodicals; Lesbians--Periodicals; Women--Periodicals; Underground press publications--Periodicals; Student movements--United States--Periodicals
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing; Politics; Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett and Elizabeth Clarke, November 2006. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, October 2025.
Custodial History
Most of the publications were collected by Professor Jerome Badanes and abandoned in the Rombout House, Vassar College. The issues of Quash and Workforce were found in the Chapel basement in 2007.
Acquisition Information
Transferred to Special Collections by Laura Streett, September 2005 and May 2007.
Container List
- Autopsy on the A.M.A. [Student Research Facility publication], circa 1971 (Box 1)
- Black and Red — No.3, 1968 Nov (Box 1)
- Black and Red — Worker and Student Action Committees, France, May '68, 1969 (Box 1)
- Black and Red — The Reproduction of Daily Life, 1969 (Box 1)
- Bread and Puppet Press — Crucifixion, 1967 Easter (Box 1)
- Bread and Puppet Press — Mr. Miller Stories, No. 3, 1967 (Box 1)
- Bread and Puppet Press — Bread and Puppet Newspaper, No. 3, 1967 Jan (Box 1)
- Caw! [Students for a Democratic Society publication] — issues 2 and 3, 1968 (Box 1)
- Hanging Loose, 1969-1974; [Some bound and shelved in the Main Library, some loose and shelved in Special Collections] (PS501. H3)
- Heresies — Issue no. 1, 1977 Jan (Box 1)
- Holocene Gazette and Country Traveller, 1970 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- Lesbian Feminist — Vol. 1, no. 1, 1973 Aug 25 (Box 1)
- Lesbian Tide — Vol. 2, no. 2, 1973 Jul (Box 1)
- Majority Report — 2 issues, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- The Militant — 1 issue, 1972 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- NACLA [North American Congress on Latin America] — The U.S. Military Apparatus, 1972 (Box 1)
- Newsletters, 1974 Jun (Box 1)
- Off Our Backs — Vol.3, no. 9, 1973 July-Aug (Box 2)
- Osawatomie [Weather Underground publication] — No. 1, 1975 Spring (Box 2)
- Quash: Newsletter of the Grand Jury Project — 2 issues, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
- The Realist: Mae Brussell's Conspiracy Newsletter, 1972 Dec (Box 2)
- Rising Up Angry — Vol. 3, no. 3-11; Vol. 4, no. 5, 7 and 8, 1972 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- The Second Wave — Vol. 1, no. 3-4, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
- Shantih, 1972 Winter/Spring (Box 2)
- Some, 1973 Winter (Box 2)
- Stray Dog, circa 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Whole Cosmep Catalog, 1973 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- Whole Earth Catalog, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- White lightning [Spirit of Logos publication] — 2 issues, circa 1971-1972 (Box 3 (Oversize))
- Win [peace and freedom through non-violent action] — misc volumes, 1969-1974 (Box 2)
- Workforce [Vocations for Social Change publication], 1974 Sep-Oct (Box 2)